The story that we're about to present does not rely on facts
It is so unlikely, that it's impossible not to believe it
It happens in that amazing time when
men worked a sabre better than grammar...
...and went without fear not only into war, but also into marriage,...
...when women knew how to value selfless love and
rewarded it with dowry,...
...when clothes were so beautiful, and figures so perfect,
that the first wasn't shameful to put on the second.
It was the time when the czar loved his people,
and the people paid him with the same,...
...well, and also with many other things.
It was the time when the best minds thought,
but kept quiet, because their mouths were forced shut,...
...and the worst, talked.
Even though, they could've kept quiet.
Well, maybe, everything wasn't like that.
If one thought about it, our story - is a tale,
barely touched up with truth.
And if one didn't think about it, even more so!
Allow me to introduce: his majesty, count Merzlyaev.
- What's there?...
...ah, it's nothing.
Count Merzlyaev, clerk for Special Orders
of the Imperial Court...
...actual secret adviser.
In one word, an influential person.
He really is an "actual" person,
and, between the two of us, in some things, secret.
Here is his valet, his coachman, his lackey,
his horses, his coach. In one word, mobile estate.
[coachman]: Prrr, slow down!
- Your majesty, in ten minutes the breakfast will be ready
- Thank you, Egorych
- Why don't you give me the pistols, darling
- Please
- What's he shooting for?
- Shooting! He's thinking! His majesty always shoots when
he thinks. During that time, he thinks of the best thoughts
- Are we coming to Gubernsk for long?
- As soon as we finish our work, we'll leave
- Egorych!
- Yes, as you say!
- Go stand over by that linden
- Your majesty, that's not a linden, that's an oak
- Yeah? Looks like a linden
- Turn towards me
- Like this?
- Yeah... the mug is that of a mongrel..
well, if we clothe you, powder you... yeah.
- And now, yell loudly,
"Satrap!"
- Your majesty, in what way?
- Well, it means, tirant, executioner, murderer. Yell!
- To whom?
- To me!
- Your majesty! I apologize for the words, but
how are you a satrap?
- You're my birthfather! [not literally]
- Yeah, keep talking. Do what you're told!
- Satrap.
- Louder.
- Satrap
- Don't worry! Louder!
- Satrap.
- Artyuhov, imagine that you're a conspirator,
a rebel. A foe to the Czar, betrayer of fatherland.
- Me?
- Yes.
- Your majesty, after so many years of faith and truth, and you..!
- No discussions!
- Satrap! Murderer! Executioner!
- So! And now, darling, fall as if you were knocked down.
- Now!
- I apologize, your majesty, legs aren't obeying!